University of Connecticut, English Department Records 1989.0001
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
University of Connecticut, English Department Records
1944-1982
1989.0001
Archives & Special Collections at the Thomas J. Dodd Research Center, University of Connecticut Libraries
1.3 Linear feet
The collection contains correspondence, reports, minutes and memoranda created and received by the English Department at the University of Connecticut.
English Department
History
The English Department is part of the College of Liberal Arts and Sciences at the University of Connecticut. It is committed to informing its majors about literature and literary history and to help them develop the writing and critical thinking skills required for literary interpretation. The English Department likewise prepares graduate students for professional careers in teaching, literary criticism, research, and writing. The department boasts a variety of programs that offer both undergraduate and graduate degrees. These include unique areas of concentration such as Irish Studies, Creative Writing, and Rhetoric and Composition. Gifted poets, novelists, essayists, and playwrights on the faculty contribute to the literary canon and provide undergraduate and graduate students with courses in creative writing. In its Freshman English courses, General Education courses, and in other upper and lower division courses, the Department serves the university community through its commitment to the teaching of critical thinking, cogent analysis, and clear written expression. Much of the Department’s research is designed to advance knowledge about literature and the cultures from which it has emerged, and to extend the critical approaches and historical perspectives through which literature can be understood and enjoyed.
For more information, please see the Department's website.
Scope and Content
The collection contains records, meeting minutes, and reports of the University of Connecticut English department. The records contain correspondence received and sent by a variety of professors in the department, as well as famous writers such as Robert Frost. There is also information on graduate programs, various areas of study within the department, and course information. Other records in the collection include materials pertaining to the English Graduate Students Association, the Federation of University Teachers, and the Committee on Black Studies. Materials in the collection date from 1944 to 1982.
For more information about the English department please visit their website at http://english.uconn.edu/
Acquisition Information
This collection was transfered to the University Archives by the English Department in 1990.
Related Material
Archives & Special Collections has a substantial collection of materials pertaining tothe University, its history, administration, faculty, staff and students. For detailed information on these collections please contact the curator or ask at the Reading Room desk.
Access
The collection is open and available for research.
University of Connecticut.; Administrative Records.; Archives.; Correspondence.; Financial Records.; Minutes.; School Records.; University of Connecticut.
- Series I: Records, undated, 1944-1982
  - Colloquim, 1966-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Committee on Black Studies, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence
    - Berryman, John, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 3-4)
    - Brinnin, John M., 1951-1976 (Box 1, Folder 5-39)
    - Duncan, Robert, 1972 (Box 1, Box 40)
    - Eberhart, Elizabeth, [1953] (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - Eberhart, Richard, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 42-48)
    - Eliot, Thomas S., 1953 (Box 1, Folder 49)
    - Frost, Robert, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 50)
    - Gaddis, William, 1966-1967 (Box 1)
    - Garrigue, Jean, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 55-56)
    - Lavin, Mary, undated, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 57-69)
    - Lowell, Robert, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 70-71)
    - MacLeish, Archibald, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 72)
    - Olson, Charles, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 73)
    - Roethke, Theodore, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 74)
    - Shapiro, Karl, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 75)
    - Spender, Stephen, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 76-90)
    - Tate, Allen, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 91)
    - Van Doren, Mark, 1953 (Box 1, Folder 92)
    - Wilbur, Richard, 1952 (Box 1, Folder 93)
    - Zukofsky, Louis, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Curriculum and Courses Committee, undated (Box 1, Folder 95-96)
  - Department Meetings, 1944-1977 (Box 1, Folder 97-99)
  - English Graduate Students Association, 1974-1977 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Executive Committee, 1968-1982 (Box 1, Folder 101-104)
  - Federation of University Teachers, 1974-1978 (Box 1, Folder 105)
  - Freshman English Courses, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 106)
  - Graduate Examination Committee, 1969-1974 (Box 1, Folder 107)
  - Graduate Placement Committee, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 108)
  - Human Rights Commission Report, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 109)
  - Inner College, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 110)
  - Irish Studies, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 111)
  - Newspaper Course, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 112)
  - Registration Committee Report, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 113)
  - Retirements: Manchester, Stallman, Warner, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 114)
  - Staff Memoranda, 1977-1982 (Box 1, Folder 115-116)
  - University Planning Exercise, Phase II, undated (Box 1, Folder 117)
  - Visiting Writer, 1971-1972 (Box 1, Folder 118)